Rory Hartong-Redden

September 10, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rory-hartong-redden | roryhr.com

Summary

Senior Data Scientist with extensive experience in product data science, data engineering, and backend engineering. I enjoy collaborating with product teams to define metrics, drive insights, and ultimately enhance the user experience. Adept at developing and deploying machine learning models and improving data foundations for long-term impact.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, Shell DevOps: AWS, Docker, Terraform, CircleCI, Git

Data Processing: Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3

 $Data\ Science\ Tools:\ pandas,\ Scikit-learn,\ Flask,\ XGBoost,\ TensorFlow,\ PySpark,\ Matplotlib$

Professional Experience

• Fast Radius (SyBridge)

Technical Manager and Data Scientist

Boulder, CO Aug 2021–May 2024

- Ensured API availability for revenue-critical services, facilitating \$10M in monthly instant quotes
- Crafted SQL queries to collect training data, monitor model accuracy, and answer adhoc questions
- Provided statistical analysis and visualization support for R&D projects involving manufacturing IoT data using Jupyter Notebooks with Python
- Fast Radius Chicago, IL

 Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021
 - Tech stack: Python, SQL, Scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS GovCloud, Datadog
 - As the founding data scientist, deployed the first machine learning model progressing from research to data munging to production deployment with Docker
 - In the startup culture I dipped into the Elixir backend, JavaScript frontend, or Terraform infrastructure to fix bugs and remove blockers

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, SQL, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" feature to bootstrap a social network and improve the retention rate
- Built a data pipeline to anonymize customer data to comply with GDPR regulations

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a research paper titled "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA Dec 2014

• University of California, Santa Barbara
BS Physics & BS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010